Guide to the Sylvester Manor Archive 1649-1996 MSS 208
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Record Group IV: Horsford Family
  - Series A: Eben N. Horsford
    Eben Norton Horsford (1818-1893), was the only son of Jerediah and Maria C. Horsford of Moscow, New York. Jerediah Horsford was a missionary to the Seneca Indians of New York and became an established expert in the language of the tribe. He would serve in the New York Assembly in 1831 and in the U.S. Congress from 1851-1853. In addition to Eben, the couple had four daughters: Maria Horsford (married name Byum), Julia Horsford (Norton), Eliza Horsford (Tryon), and Laura Horsford. E.N. Horsford attended Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute (RPI), graduating in 1838 with a civil engineering degree. He then was employed on the Geographical Survey of New York, working under James Hall, a noted geologist and paleontologist also from RPI. From 1840-1844 E.N. Horsford was a professor of Mathematics and Science at the Albany Female Academy, a higher education institution for women. Here he would meet Mary and Phoebe Gardiner as students. During this same period, E.N. lectured at Newark College in Delaware, which later became the University of Delaware. In 1844, Horsford left the U.S. to study with noted chemist Justus von Liebig in Giessen, Germany, where he would remain for three years. Upon his return to the U.S., Horsford was chosen as the Rumford Professor and Lecturer on the Application of Science to the Useful Arts at Harvard University, where he would remain, teaching and publishing steadily until 1863. He would leave to focus his attention on the Rumford Chemical Works, a company he began in 1854 with George F. Wilson, who primarily ran the operational side of the business, to commercially produce Horsford’s chemical inventions and developments. The endeavor would make Horsford quite wealthy. Horsford’s most successful development was the modern formula for baking powder, but he also produced acid phosphate, anti-chlorine, yeast powder, and developed a process for condensing milk. During the end of the U.S. Civil War, Horsford put much time and energy into developing an “improved army ration” that involved the use of dehydrated meat; but although the project won the attention of several high ranking military and civilian leaders, it was never adopted. Rumford also developed a new method of manufacturing fire-proof safes, an improved method for attaching armor plating to warships, and conducted water analyses for municipalities in the Boston area. In 1873 Horsford was selected as a member of the U.S. Scientific Commission for the Weltausstellung 1873 Wien, or Vienna Exposition. Later in his life he became interested in the study of the “lost” city of Norumbega, which Horsford believed was a settlement of Viking explorers located in present Weston, Massachusetts. He published several treatises on the issue beginning in 1889, and had a monument erected to mark the supposed location of the settlement. Horsford’s findings on Norumbega and the Northmen have come to be generally disregarded. His appointment to Harvard convinced Samuel Gardiner to allow his daughter Mary L’Hommedieu Gardiner to wed E.N., and the two were married in 1847. Mary gave birth to four daughters: Mary Leila (Lilian) in 1848, Mary Catherine (Kate) in 1850, Gertrude Hubbard in 1852, and Mary Gardiner (Mamie) in 1855. Mary died a few months after the birth of Mamie. E.N. Horsford then married Mary’s sister Phoebe in 1857, and the couple had one daughter, Cornelia Conway Felton, in 1860. The Horsfords led an active social life centered on their Cambridge and Harvard communities. E.N. Horsford and his family were acquainted with several members of the “Boston Brahmin” as well as prominent figures of the Cambridge intelligentsia and literary community, including Oliver Wendell Holmes, Sr., Henry Longfellow, Sarah Orne Jewett, and Helen Hunt Jackson to name but a few. Horsford strongly supported female education and became closely involved with Wellesley College, becoming president of its Board of Visitors in 1877, and honorary class member of the Class of 1886. He was close with Henry Fowle Durant, the school’s first president, and corresponded voluminously with students, teachers, and later presidents and administrators. On January 1, 1893, E.N. Horsford died at his home in Cambridge.
    This series contains E.N. Horsford’s papers, including correspondence, financial documents, scientific papers and writings, business documents, Norumbega research materials, newspapers and clippings, maps, and visual materials.
    - Subseries 1: Correspondence
      - Subsubseries a: Family/General
        - Sophie Fela Achorny, 1889 (Box 55, Folder 17)
        - Lyman Abbott, 1887 (Box 55, Folder 18)
        - M.V. Abbott, undated (Box 55, Folder 19)
        - O. B. Ackerly, 1883 (Box 55, Folder 20)
        - C.F. Adams, Jr., 1882 (Box 55, Folder 21)
        - C. Adewald [?], 1869 (Box 55, Folder 22)
        - Elizabeth C. Agassiz, undated (Box 55, Folder 23)
        - Albany Female Academy, 1839, 1841, 1842, undated (Box 55, Folder 24)
        - Mary L. Aldrich, undated (Box 55, Folder 25)
        - James Edward Alexander, 1880 (Box 55, Folder 26)
        - J. E. Alexander (Shreve, Crump and Low Jewelers), 1887 (Box 55, Folder 27)
        - James Allen, 1858 (Box 55, Folder 28)
        - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1878, 1887 (Box 55, Folder 29)
        - American Association for the Advancement of Science, undated (Box 55, Folder 30)
        - American Bell Telephone Company, 1877, 1882, 1885 (Box 55, Folder 31)
        - American Copyright League, undated (Box 55, Folder 32)
        - American Loan and Trust Company, 1886 (Box 55, Folder 33)
        - American Metrological Society, 1886 (Box 55, Folder 34)
        - American Philosophical Society, 1849 (Box 55, Folder 35)
        - American Social Science Association, 1889 (Box 55, Folder 36)
        - B. B. Anderson, 1881 (Box 55, Folder 37)
        - Frimann B. Anderson, 1889 (Box 55, Folder 38)
        - M.B. Anderson, 1878 (Box 55, Folder 39)
        - Frank W. Andrews, 1887 (Box 55, Folder 40)
        - Lucy C. Andrews, 1887 (Box 55, Folder 41)
        - A.T. Andson, 1844 (Box 55, Folder 42)
        - H.M. Anthony, 1878 (Box 55, Folder 43)
        - Appalachian Mountain Club, 1890 (Box 55, Folder 44)
        - C.E. Appleton, 1877, undated (Box 55, Folder 45)
        - John H. Appleton, 1881 (Box 55, Folder 46)
        - T.G. Appleton, 1877 (Box 55, Folder 47)
        - The Archaelogical Institute of America, undated (Box 55, Folder 48)
        - W.S. Archer, 1889 (Box 55, Folder 49)
        - Dr. Arness [?], 1889 (Box 55, Folder 50)
        - Alex A. Arthur, 1887 (Box 55, Folder 51)
        - F. B. Arugrinson, 1889 (Box 55, Folder 52)
        - Association of American Geologists and Naturalists (B. Silliman), 1843 (Box 55, Folder 53)
        - Atlantic and West India Line (H. George Irrick?), 1887 (Box 55, Folder 54)
        - Charles Avery, 1840 (Box 55, Folder 55)
        - Walter Ayraum, 1842 (Box 55, Folder 56)
        - C.L.B., 1843 (Box 55, Folder 57)
        - A. Barker (Office of U.S. Light House Inspector, 2nd District), 1888 (Box 55, Folder 58)
        - Josiah Bacon (Goodyear Dental Vulcanite Company), 1868 (Box 55, Folder 59)
        - L.J. Bacon, 1887 (Box 55, Folder 60)
        - N.A. Bacon, 1843 (Box 55, Folder 61)
        - S.Y. Bacon, 1868 (Box 55, Folder 62)
        - John Bagshaw, 1887 (Box 55, Folder 63)
        - James Bain, Jr. (Public Library of Toronto), 1889 (Box 55, Folder 64)
        - William Emerson Baker ("Alice M" Chemical Club), 1877 (Box 55, Folder 65)
        - Ad. F. Bandelin, 1887 (Box 55, Folder 66)
        - Thomas G. Banks, 1889 (Box 55, Folder 67)
        - Frederick A. P. Barnard, 1874-1875, 1886 (Box 55, Folder 68)
        - M.P. Barnard, 1890 (Box 55, Folder 69)
        - George G. Barnum (Buffalo Historical Society), 1889, 1890 (Box 55, Folder 70)
        - Herman N. Barnum, 1887 (Box 55, Folder 71)
        - P.T. Barnum, 1878 (Box 55, Folder 72)
        - John Manning Barrons, 1887 (Box 55, Folder 73)
        - Marion E.H. Barrows, 1889 (Box 55, Folder 74)
        - W. Barrows, 1889 (Box 55, Folder 75)
        - Ephraim L. Barry, 1889 (Box 55, Folder 76)
        - Johann Bartersh [?], 1883 (Box 56, Folder 1)
        - John Bartlett, 1881, 1889 (Box 56, Folder 2)
        - John Batchelder, 1889 (Box 56, Folder 3)
        - C.H. Bateman, 1889 (Box 56, Folder 4)
        - Charlotte Fiske Bates, 1886 (Box 56, Folder 5)
        - James P. Baxter, 1889 (Box 56, Folder 6)
        - Sylvester Baxter, 1882, 1886-1887, 1889-1890 (Box 56, Folder 7)
        - M.Y. Beach (The Berkshire County Eagle), 1890 (Box 56, Folder 8)
        - M.C. Beale, 1887, 1889, undated (Box 56, Folder 9)
        - J.H. Beatty, 1887 (Box 56, Folder 10)
        - W.M. Beauchamp, 1887 (Box 56, Folder 11)
        - Arthur Bell (Howard Insurance Company), 1887 (Box 56, Folder 12)
        - Clark Bell, undated (Box 56, Folder 13)
        - Jack Benjamin [?], undated (Box 56, Folder 14)
        - Marcus Benjamin, 1887 (Box 56, Folder 15)
        - Bergen, Norway - miscellaneous correspondence (as originally foldered), 1882, 1883 (Box 56, Folder 16)
        - Valustrin Bertter, 1863-1864 (Box 56, Folder 17)
        - Emily M. Biddle, undated (Box 56, Folder 18)
        - M.B. Bigelow and Anson Hardy, 1863 (Box 56, Folder 19)
        - M.D. Bisbee (Dartmouth College), 1889 (Box 56, Folder 20)
        - Lucy A. Bissell, 1887, 1889 (Box 56, Folder 21)
        - Charles F. Blake, 1868 (Box 56, Folder 22)
        - Clarence F. Blake, 1878 (Box 56, Folder 23)
        - Irving Blake, 1887 (Box 56, Folder 24)
        - Maurice Bloomfield, 1887 (Box 56, Folder 25)
        - F. Bocher, 1887 (Box 56, Folder 26)
        - J.P. Bodfish, 1888-1889 (Box 56, Folder 27)
        - C.E. Bolton (Bolton's Realistic Travels), 1889 (Box 56, Folder 28)
        - H. Carrington Bolton, 1887 (Box 56, Folder 29)
        - James C. Booth, 1844, 1868 (Box 56, Folder 30)
        - A. Borden, 1884 (Box 56, Folder 31)
        - Gail Borden, 1864-1865 (Box 56, Folder 32)
        - Richard P. Borden, 1890 (Box 56, Folder 33)
        - Boston North End Mission, 1887, 1889 (Box 56, Folder 34)
        - Boston Public Library, 1887 (Box 56, Folder 35)
        - Boston Ornamental Iron Works, 1887 (Box 56, Folder 36)
        - George S. Bostwell, 1889 (Box 56, Folder 37)
        - Gisle Bothne, 1889 (Box 56, Folder 38)
        - J.B. Bowditch, T.M. Havens, Matthew Payne, C.H. Bateman and N.P. Dickerson, 1874 (Box 56, Folder 39)
        - Francis Bowen, 1887 (Box 56, Folder 40)
        - Clarence W. Bowen, 1889 (Box 56, Folder 41)
        - George W. Boyd to Jas P. Kimball, 1889 (Box 56, Folder 42)
        - G. Bradford (American Social Science Association), 1878 (Box 56, Folder 43)
        - Lawrence Bradford, 1888 (Box 56, Folder 44)
        - Sarah H. Bradford, 1889-1890, undated (Box 56, Folder 45)
        - Brazen Achuminate, 1890 (Box 56, Folder 46)
        - Luis Bramsen, 1843 (Box 56, Folder 47)
        - C.P. Branson, 1842 (Box 56, Folder 48)
        - Jon Bratt, 1842 (Box 56, Folder 49)
        - Charles G. Bremdige, 1839 (Box 56, Folder 50)
        - J.C. Brevoort, 1887 (Box 56, Folder 51)
        - Arnold W. Brewer, 1887 (Box 56, Folder 52)
        - Captain Brewerton, 1843 (Box 56, Folder 53)
        - George D. Brewerton to E.N. Horsford, 1842-1843, undated (Box 56, Folder 54)
        - Elizabeth Briggs, 1887 (Box 56, Folder 55)
        - Martin Briggs [with clipping], 1864-1865 (Box 56, Folder 56)
        - Edwin H. Brigham, 1890 (Box 56, Folder 57)
        - M.A. Brigham, 1887 (Box 56, Folder 58)
        - William Brigham, 1887 (Box 56, Folder 59)
        - Emma M. Bright, 1841 (Box 56, Folder 60)
        - Sarah Brinley, 1887-1889 (Box 56, Folder 61)
        - D.G. Brinton, 1887, undated (Box 56, Folder 62)
        - Benj. Brodie, undated (Box 56, Folder 63)
        - John Brooks (St. Helena Gold Mine), 1883-1884 (Box 56, Folder 64)
        - Lloyd Broome, 1887 (Box 56, Folder 65)
        - Adelaide Brown, 1889 (Box 56, Folder 66)
        - Alexander Brown, 1889 (Box 56, Folder 67)
        - Anna R. Brown, 1889 (Box 56, Folder 68)
        - A.W. Brown, 1889 (Box 56, Folder 69)
        - John Nicholas Brown, 1887 (Box 56, Folder 70)
        - Marie Brown, 1889 (Box 56, Folder 71)
        - Otis S. Brown (Cambridge Republican Ward and City Committee), 1887 (Box 56, Folder 72)
        - Charles Brundige, 1837-1842 (Box 56, Folder 73)
        - Helen C. Brunsan, 1887 (Box 56, Folder 74)
        - C.N. Buell (Grandmother), 1837, 1840 (Box 56, Folder 75)
        - George C. Buell, 1878, 1889 (Box 56, Folder 76)
        - James M. Bugler, 1889 (Box 56, Folder 77)
        - Alexander Bull, 1876, 1880-1881, 1889 (Box 56, Folder 78)
        - Sara V. Bull, 1884, 1887, 1889, undated (Box 56, Folder 79)
        - Harriette L. Bunker, 1887 (Box 56, Folder 80)
        - William E. Burchard, 1833, 1836 (Box 56, Folder 81)
        - Bureau of Education, Department of the Interior, 1887 (Box 56, Folder 82)
        - C.C. Burns [?], 1884 (Box 56, Folder 83)
        - James Burns, 1867 (Box 56, Folder 84)
        - John Burns, 1876 (Box 56, Folder 85)
        - Patrick Burns, 1862-1864 (Box 57, Folder 1)
        - Charles C. Burr, E.S. Mansfield and H.M. Moore (St. Helena Gold Mine), 1887 (Box 57, Folder 2)
        - George L. Burr, 1889 (Box 57, Folder 3)
        - Henry T. Burrage, 1889 (Box 57, Folder 4)
        - W.M. Burrows, 1887 (Box 57, Folder 5)
        - Albert Bushnell*MISSING, 1890
        - John Buxton, 1841 (Box 57, Folder 6)
        - John Byer, 1887 (Box 57, Folder 7)
        - Norton H. Byam, 1887, 1889, undated (Box 57, Folder 8)
        - W.E. Byerly, 1884, 1887, 1890 (Box 57, Folder 9)
        - J.C.C., undated (Box 57, Folder 10)
        - J. Elliot Cabot, 1887 (Box 57, Folder 11)
        - Call and Tuttle, 1889 (Box 57, Folder 12)
        - Calling cards 1 of 2, circa 1880 (Box 57, Folder 13)
        - Calling cards 2 of 2, circa 1880 (Box 57, Folder 14)
        - Calling cards, notes and small illustration gathered in envelope, circa 1887 (Box 57, Folder 15)
        - Calling cards 1 of 3, circa 1889-1890 (Box 57, Folder 16)
        - Calling cards 2 of 3, circa 1889-1890 (Box 57, Folder 17)
        - Calling cards 3 of 3, circa 1889-1890 (Box 57, Folder 18)
        - Calling cards 1 of 2, undated (Box 57, Folder 19)
        - Calling cards 2 of 2, undated (Box 57, Folder 20)
        - G.H. Calvert, 1887 (Box 57, Folder 21)
        - John Campbell, 1887 (Box 57, Folder 22)
        - Cambridge Public Library, 1890 (Box 57, Folder 23)
        - Thomas Carew, 1887 (Box 57, Folder 24)
        - E.H. Carpenter, 1872 (Box 57, Folder 25)
        - Albertson Carr, 1872 (Box 57, Folder 26)
        - E.S. Carr, 1838-1844 (Box 58, Folder 1)
        - Ezra and Jeanne Carr, 1882 (Box 58, Folder 2)
        - A.S. Cartwright, 1887 (Box 58, Folder 3)
        - B.C. Cartwright, 1887-1888 (Box 58, Folder 4)
        - J. Wickham Case, 1884 (Box 58, Folder 5)
        - Samuel Chapman, 1842 (Box 58, Folder 6)
        - Chase and Barstow, 1884 (Box 58, Folder 7)
        - George C. Chase, 1886 (Box 58, Folder 8)
        - Thomas Chase, 1887 (Box 58, Folder 9)
        - Charles A. Cheever, 1887 (Box 58, Folder 10)
        - John H. Cheever, 1868 (Box 58, Folder 11)
        - A.T. Chester, 1841-1842 (Box 58, Folder 12)
        - E. Chester, 1839 (Box 58, Folder 13)
        - Joseph L. Chester, 1839-1840 (Box 58, Folder 14)
        - Joseph L. Chester, 1841-1842 (Box 58, Folder 15)
        - Joseph L. Chester, 1842-1843 (Box 58, Folder 16)
        - Joseph L. Chester, 1876 (Box 58, Folder 17)
        - F. J. Child, undated (Box 58, Folder 18)
        - N.A. Childs, 1872, 1875 (Box 58, Folder 19)
        - Choate and Barnes (re Bowery Property), 1859 (Box 58, Folder 20)
        - C.F. Choate, 1880 (Box 58, Folder 21)
        - Joseph H. Choate, 1864 (Box 58, Folder 22)
        - F.W. Christern, 1886-1890 (Box 58, Folder 23)
        - Alfred Christiansen, 1887 (Box 58, Folder 24)
        - Cincinnati Pork Packers' Association to W.P. Moschine, 1893 (Box 58, Folder 25)
        - Henry Clark (Rutland County Historical Society), 1887 (Box 58, Folder 26)
        - Addison Cleaves, 1887 (Box 58, Folder 27)
        - C. Clemm, 1873 (Box 58, Folder 28)
        - J. Morton Clinch, 1889 (Box 58, Folder 29)
        - William Argyle Clutson, 1897 (Box 58, Folder 30)
        - Francis Coaker, 1889 December 30 (Box 58, Folder 31)
        - R. Coates [?], 1840 (Box 58, Folder 32)
        - L.W. Coe, September 3, 1967 (Box 58, Folder 33)
        - Charles Carleton Coffin, undated (Box 58, Folder 34)
        - Ella F. Cole, 1887 (Box 58, Folder 35)
        - E.L. Collins, 1887 (Box 58, Folder 36)
        - George Combe, 1840 (Box 58, Folder 37)
        - to the Committee on Math (Albany Female Academy), undated (Box 58, Folder 38)
        - The Congressional Club, 1889 (Box 58, Folder 39)
        - Charles Cotton, 1835 (Box 58, Folder 40)
        - E. Miriam Coyriere, 1887 (Box 58, Folder 41)
        - W. Crawford, 1844 (Box 58, Folder 42)
        - A. Crittenton (Albany Female Academy), 1842-1844, 1877, 1881-1882, undated (Box 58, Folder 43)
        - Howard Crosby, 1889 (Box 58, Folder 44)
        - Mary Bradford Crowenishield [?], 1887 (Box 58, Folder 45)
        - George W. Cullum, 1887 (Box 58, Folder 46)
        - Benjamin R. Curtis, 1881-1890 (Box 58, Folder 47)
        - Benjamin R. Curtis, Jr., 1891 (Box 58, Folder 48)
        - Benjamin R. Curtis, Jr. and Mary Curtis, 1891 (Box 58, Folder 49)
        - D.S. Curtis, 1835 (Box 58, Folder 50)
        - Helena Curtis, undated (Box 58, Folder 51)
        - Mary Gardiner Curtis (Granddaughter), 1881, undated (Box 58, Folder 52)
        - Emily J.M. Cushing, undated (Box 58, Folder 53)
        - Frank Hamilton Cushing, 1883-1887 (Box 58, Folder 54)
        - C.A. Cuttier (Boston Athenaeu), 1887 (Box 58, Folder 55)
        - Joseph T. D[?], 1887 (Box 58, Folder 56)
        - H. Daightly, 1840 (Box 58, Folder 57)
        - Charlotte Dailey, undated (Box 58, Folder 58)
        - Charles P. Daly, 1886-1889 (Box 58, Folder 59)
        - Otto Dammer, 1875 (Box 58, Folder 60)
        - Damrell and Upham, 1889 (Box 58, Folder 61)
        - Edith L. Dana, undated (Box 58, Folder 62)
        - James D. Dana, 1843 (Box 58, Folder 63)
        - Annie N. Darling, 1887 (Box 58, Folder 64)
        - C.W. Darling, 1889 (Box 58, Folder 65)
        - B.F. Davenport, 1889 (Box 58, Folder 66)
        - Ira Davenport and D. Bauder (Pleasant Valley Wine Company), 1876, 1884 (Box 58, Folder 67)
        - Anna B. Davidson, 1889 (Box 58, Folder 68)
        - Charles Davidson [?] Department of Justice, 1877 (Box 58, Folder 69)
        - Theodore F. Davidson, 1887 (Box 58, Folder 70)
        - Davies and Work, 1871 (Box 58, Folder 71)
        - Edward L. Davis, 1890 (Box 58, Folder 72)
        - George Davis, 1889 (Box 58, Folder 73)
        - N. Danell Davis (re Barbadian History), 1887 (Box 58, Folder 74)
        - W.M. Davis (New England Metrological Society), 1887 (Box 58, Folder 75)
        - William J. Davis, 1887 (Box 58, Folder 76)
        - Clement M. Davison, 1842-1843 (Box 59, Folder 1)
        - George Davison, 1889 (Box 59, Folder 2)
        - Delia P. Day, 1890 (Box 59, Folder 3)
        - John Ward Dean, 1887 (Box 59, Folder 4)
        - Charles A. Deane, 1885, 1887 (Box 59, Folder 5)
        - Mary H. Deane, undated (Box 59, Folder 6)
        - B.F. DeCosta, 1886-1887, 1889 (Box 59, Folder 7)
        - N. Dellap [?], undated (Box 59, Folder 8)
        - Delta Phi Society, 1844 (Box 59, Folder 9)
        - Mary M. DeVerry, 1884 (Box 59, Folder 10)
        - C. Dewey, 1837, 1843, 1862-1863 (Box 59, Folder 11)
        - Melvil Dewey, 1884-1888, undated (Box 59, Folder 12)
        - Samuel Dewey, 1887 (Box 59, Folder 13)
        - Franklin Dowditch Dexter, 1889 (Box 59, Folder 14)
        - Henry M. Dexter, 1889 (Box 59, Folder 15)
        - Diebold, Bahmann and Company, 1864-1865 (Box 59, Folder 16)
        - Estelle E. Doremus, 1887, 1889 (Box 59, Folder 17)
        - N. Ogden Doremus, 1889 (Box 59, Folder 18)
        - L.L. Doty, 1860 (Box 59, Folder 19)
        - Samuel Doughty, 1887 (Box 59, Folder 20)
        - Eduna (?) H. Drake, 1841, 1843 (Box 59, Folder 21)
        - C.B. Dresser, 1881 (Box 59, Folder 22)
        - F. Dubben (Norddeutscher Lloyd), 1890 (Box 59, Folder 23)
        - D. Bethune Duffield (Duffield & Duffield), 1889, undated (Box 59, Folder 24)
        - C. Dugraham, 1843 (Box 59, Folder 25)
        - D.J. Duhig (?) (Boston Post Office), 1887 (Box 59, Folder 26)
        - Charles L. Dunbar, 1889 (Box 59, Folder 27)
        - E.P. Dutton and Company, 1888 (Box 59, Folder 28)
        - Elisa S. Dutton, 1834-1835 (Box 59, Folder 29)
        - W.C. Dwight and M.C. Horsford, 1842 (Box 59, Folder 30)
        - Louis Dyer, 1887 (Box 59, Folder 31)
        - G. [?] Dyott, undated (Box 59, Folder 32)
        - J.P.E., 1842 (Box 59, Folder 33)
        - Amos Eaton, 1837-1838 (Box 59, Folder 34)
        - L.A. Eaton, undated (Box 59, Folder 35)
        - Thomas T. Eckert (Western Union Telegraph), 1887 (Box 59, Folder 36)
        - Richard Eddy, 1887 (Box 59, Folder 37)
        - Winfred Edgerton, 1887 (Box 59, Folder 38)
        - Fannie Edmond, 1887 (Box 59, Folder 39)
        - Charles W. Elliott, 1876, undated (Box 59, Folder 40)
        - Henry N. Elliott, 1889 (Box 59, Folder 41)
        - to Alfred L. Elwyre, 1849-1850 (Box 59, Folder 42)
        - Sara Ely, 1887 (Box 59, Folder 43)
        - George B. Emerton, 1843 (Box 59, Folder 44)
        - G.H. Emery, 1890 (Box 59, Folder 45)
        - John Ericsson, 1862-1866, 1878 (Box 59, Folder 46)
        - C.W. Ernst, 1887, 1890 (Box 59, Folder 47)
        - James P. Espy, 1841, 1844 (Box 59, Folder 48)
        - D. Ettling, 1846 (Box 59, Folder 49)
        - Charles Evans, 1889 (Box 59, Folder 50)
        - Edward Everett, 1847, 1849 (Box 59, Folder 51)
        - W. Faber, 1843 (Box 59, Folder 52)
        - Luther Farnham, 1887 (Box 59, Folder 53)
        - Joseph S. Fay, 1887, 1889 (Box 59, Folder 54)
        - Levi C. Ferry, 1839-1841 (Box 59, Folder 55)
        - Cyrus W. Field, 1878 (Box 59, Folder 56)
        - Henry M. Field, 1889 (Box 59, Folder 57)
        - Mary J. Field, 1889 (Box 59, Folder 58)
        - Annie Fields, 1881-1886, 1893, undated (Box 59, Folder 59)
        - Fannie Washington Finch, 1886 (Box 59, Folder 60)
        - The First Church of Cambridge, 1887 (Box 59, Folder 61)
        - First National Bank of Breenport, 1872 (Box 59, Folder 62)
        - to Miss Fisher, 1891 (Box 59, Folder 63)
        - Hamilton Fisk (US Department of State) (Vienna Exposition), 1876 (Box 59, Folder 64)
        - Andrew Fiske, 1886-1889 (Box 59, Folder 65)
        - Augustus Henry Fiske, undated (Box 59, Folder 66)
        - C.H. Fiske, 1886, 1889 (Box 59, Folder 67)
        - Gertrude Fiske (granddaughter), 1887-1890, undated (Box 59, Folder 68)
        - John Fiske, 1889 (Box 59, Folder 69)
        - Mr. and Mrs. Fiske, 1887 (Box 60, Folder 1)
        - William Addison Fitzhugh, 1834-1835 (Box 60, Folder 2)
        - Charles L. Flint (New England Historic Genealogical Society), 1886 (Box 60, Folder 3)
        - George C. Flint, 1886 (Box 60, Folder 4)
        - L.J. Flint, 1880 (Box 60, Folder 5)
        - B.F. Foley, Sarah L. Foley - addressed, unstamped envelopes, 1887 (Box 60, Folder 6)
        - Folk Lore Publication Society, undated (Box 60, Folder 7)
        - A.A. Folsom, 1889-1890 (Box 60, Folder 8)
        - George W. Folsom, 1889 (Box 60, Folder 9)
        - Henry W. Foote (Prince Society), 1887 (Box 60, Folder 10)
        - Paul Leicester Ford, 1887, 1889-1890 (Box 60, Folder 11)